AHMED EL-ZEIN

UI/UX & GRAPHIC DESIGNER

I am a senior level designer with 7+ years of experience. A professional designer with top level skills in Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, in Design, and XD. As an industry professional, I've completed projects such as branding, websites, apps, marketing and advertisment campaigns.







🔐 Ottawa, Ontario, Canada 📞 +1 (613) 600-9794 🖾 elzeindesigns@gmail.com 📮 ahmedelzein.ca 🛅 linkedin.com/in/ahmed-el-zein

EDUCATION

Graphic Design

Algonquin College | Sept. 2013- Apr. 2016

- Dean's List Academic Year 2015-2016
- Cumulative G.P.A. of 3.75/4

GAS - Design Studies

Algonquin College | Sept. 2012- Apr. 2013

- Dean's List Academic Year 2012
- Cumulative G.P.A. of 3.4/4

SKILLS

Software Skills

- Adobe CC Graphic Design
- HTML5/ Drupal/ Bootstrap
- CSS3/SCSS/Javascript/Jquery
- Microsoft Office & iWork

Personal Skills

- Fluent in English, French, and Arabic
- Creative & Critical Thinker
- Self-Motivated & Detail Oriented
- Problem Solving & Active Listener

Knowledge

- Branding, Typography & Colour Theory
- User Research & Strategy
- Wireframing & Prototyping
- Responsive Design
- Visual Communication

HOBBIES

- Reading
- Basketball
- Fitness
- Video games

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Design Services

El-Zein Design Services | May 2014- Present

Established a design agency that focuses on branding, web and print services, user interface and experience, and illustration. Designed for clients in multiple industries such as; broadcasting, health, trade, real estate, food, and education.

- Created brand guidelines and identities
- Produced print content such as the stationery package, posters, brochures, menus, reports, and flyers.
- Designed and developed business websites, an educational website, non-profit website, an eCommerce website, and a portfolio website.
- Created ads for social media which increased sales by 10%

Graphic Designer

Department of National Defence of Canada | Sept. 2019- Aug. 2020

The department is responsible for defending Canada's interests and values at home and abroad, as well as contributing to international peace and security. I joined the CRO (Community Relations & Outreach) team which focused on promotion for internal and external events.

- Designed infographics and posters for print and web
- Created the Canadian Army Podcast brand
- Responsible for the daily posts on all social media accounts
- Designed the Canadian Forces Parachutist badges

Digital Designer

Klipfolio | Sept. 2016-Sept. 2019

Klipfolio is a data analytics cloud app for building and sharing real-time data. I joined the marketing team to drive sales and growth. I earned two certificates of excellence for my contribution on marketing campaigns.

- Created the brand guidelines and the visual language
- Developed and designed over 80+ user-friendly webpages
- · Carried out usability tests to increase user statisfaction
- Designed and updated the user interface across the website
- Designed landing pages which drove conversions by 12%
- Designed ads across all social media accounts which increased sales by 8%
- Coached marketing teammates at improving website coding skills